Kyle Romero, Director of Software Development

Jersey City, NJ, 07311, (281) 857-9006, kgromero@gmail.com

LINKS	kgromero.com, linkedin.com/in/kyleromero/
PROFILE	IT Leader with 10 years as a full-stack developer and 6 years in software development management. Looking for the next opportunity to lead a development organization to success, maximize business value, and provide a greatuser experience.
TECHNOLOGIES	Processes: DevOps, CICD, Agile Scrum, Kanban, GitFlow, Matrixed Organization
	.NET: C#, VB.NET, ASP.NET API/MVC, Blazor, UWP
	JavaScript: React, Node.js, NPM, Electron, Angular, TypeScript, SvelteKit
	Scripting: Python
	Web: HTML, CSS, Tailwind
	Containerization (Novice): Docker, Kubernetes
	DB: SQL Server, Sqlite3, Oracle
	Reporting: SSRS, PowerBI
	Cloud: Azure, AWS, Netlify
	Servers: Windows Server, Linux (Ubuntu/Debian)
	Tooling: Azure DevOps, GitHub, Visual Studio/VS Code, SSMS, DBeaver
	Data: Boomi, SSIS
	Other: Sharepoint Online, PowerApps, PowerAutomate, Twilio, JWT, Swagger, C++

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Mar 2023 — May 2024

Director of Software Development, Raymour & Flanigan

Jersey City, NJ (remote)

Leadership

- Team Size: 3 Managers (.NET Team, Oracle Team, Boomi Team), 4 Architects, 30 Developers (mix of
 internal and near/off shore resources)
- Aligned teams within internal matrixed organization (QA / Product Teams)
- Defined and executed organizational strategy, including transformational 5 year vision
- Recruited and retained skilled resources for organization, growing headcount by 10%
- · Held weekly 1:1's and annual reviews with direct reports and bi-annual skip-level 1:1's with indirect reports
- Visited northeast US locations to check-in with user base (5% of time)

Technical

- Largest Initiatives: Order Management Tool Upgrade (UWP App), ERP Migration to NetSuite, WMS Migration to Korber, Omnichannel Sales Experience, 3rd Party Integrations (ChargeAfter, Bringg), Data Domain API and Boomi Standup
- Directly led change control and release management processes, leading to 50% decrease in production defect rate
- Acted as SME alongside architects (direct reports) to define and executive organizational architecture strategy. On-Call alongside architects on a rotating basis with 100% coverage

Financial

- Forecasted and controlled organizational budget and credit card, reducing costs by 25%
- Performed invoice review and approval process for organization, leading to 100% on-time payments
- Negotiated, reviewed, and managed development partner (near-shore / on-shore) and vendor contracts / resources, which reduced contract costs by 40%
- Coordinated with infrastructure team to monitor and control cloud and on-premises costs

Leadership

- Team Size: 4 Developers, 1 PM, 7 Offshore. 100% remote team.
- Executed organizational strategy and maintained executive and customer relationships
- Managed yearly software development internship programs on 5 separate occasions
- Traveled to U.S. locations to roll out applications (25% of time)
- Directly reported to CIO

Technical

- Largest Application: Mission Critical SOX-compliant internally developed Field Capture solution, used by over 700 field construction crews across the US. This solution sped up the closing process by 75%
- Acted as technical expert on tech stack and helped explore and implement new technologies
- Implemented and trained organization on DevOps/CICD, Agile Scrum, GitFlow, and QA processes, which increased delivery speed by 50%
- Designated and documented all architecture and SDLC for the organization and led change management process while rolling out applications
- Administered systems such as Azure DevOps, Sharepoint Online, Power Automate, PowerBI, and Azure

Financial

- · Forecasted and maintained organizational budget, coming out on-budget every year
- · Onboarded and coordinated offshore development partner based out of India

Apr 2016 — Oct 2017

Team Lead / Senior Developer, Worldwide Machinery

Houston, TX

- · Led internal software development team and reported to co-owner of company
- Full-stack development using .NET, MS SQL, and React which delivered mission-critical asset management software (desktop, mobile, and web)

Dec 2011 — Feb 2016

Technical Lead (IT Developer / Engineer III), HP Inc.

Houston, TX

- Designated as technical lead over mission-critical third level support tool with 10k+ users
- Full-stack development delivering 3-tier web applications using .NET, MS SQL, and JavaScript
- Gained exposure to big data (Hadoop / HP Vertica) and BI/analytics (PowerBI / Tableau)

Aug 2007 — Dec 2011

Software / Systems Engineer, X-Fab, Texas

Lubbock, TX

- Full-Stack developer specializing in .NET, MS SQL, C++, and Perle development
- Built 3-tier web applications and hardware monitoring solutions and introduced Subversion source control to company

May 2007 — Jul 2007

Software Development Intern, Texas Tech / X-Fab, Texas

Lubbock, TX

- Full-stack development internship with emphasis on C++ and .NET development
- Completed a statistical analysis application and a file format conversion program

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering,

Texas Tech University

SKILLS

People Management

Software Development

Financial Management

Agile Scrum

System Architecture

DevOps

ACHIEVEMENTS

2021: Promoted to Director of Operations Technology

2021: Nominated to MEARS Group Innovator Team (Company Think-Tank)

2021: Nominated to Quanta Services Leadership Academy

2020: Promoted to Senior Manager of Operations Technology

2013: Promoted to Technical Lead (IT Developer/Engineer III)